<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thomas Chavakis</title>
    <link>https://tomchavakis.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Thomas Chavakis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 11:40:49 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tomchavakis.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Visual studio code extensions for teams</title>
      <link>https://tomchavakis.github.io/posts/visual-studio-code-for-coding-teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 11:40:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tomchavakis.github.io/posts/visual-studio-code-for-coding-teams/</guid>
      <description>What ? Visual Studio Code is a cross-platform code editor made by Microsoft. There are more than 30.000 Extensions available to the marketplace of the visual studio code which turns the tool into a powerful, multi-language and multipurpose IDE.
The teams need to have common tools for the day to day work. When you change programs it&amp;rsquo;s easy to get distracted, lose your focus and your purpose. With the following extensions, you can do the biggest part of your work within the visual studio code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Documentation Before Development</title>
      <link>https://tomchavakis.github.io/posts/documentation-before-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 12:18:30 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tomchavakis.github.io/posts/documentation-before-development/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Documentation Before Development (DBD), is an agile way of working within a software development team.
Every agile team in the software industry has to release products quickly and frequently, and usually documents the processes followed at the very end of the project.
The DBD process was created to address the problems arising when software teams start the delopment phase without analyzing in depth what is going to be delivered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to optimally alter mysql tables using percona-tools</title>
      <link>https://tomchavakis.github.io/posts/how-to-optimally-alter-mysql-tables-using-percona-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 12:13:30 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tomchavakis.github.io/posts/how-to-optimally-alter-mysql-tables-using-percona-tools/</guid>
      <description>Introduction You have to be very carefull when you are going to run an ALTER Table in the production Database. MySQL&amp;rsquo;s ALTER TABLE can become a serious problem especially with very large tables. Many people have experience with ALTER TABLE operations that have taken hours or days to complete.
From the MySQL documentation for ALTER TABLE:
ALTER TABLE changes the structure of a table. The operations are processed using one of the following algorithms:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://tomchavakis.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tomchavakis.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Thomas Chavakis. I&amp;rsquo;m a Software Engineer &amp;amp; Web Developer, specializing in designing large-scale web applications and microServices using GoLang and Microsoft Technologies. I&amp;rsquo;ve worked in different environments, organisations and private companies, but for me the most important thing is the team and challenges.
I have a BSc in Computer Science, an MSc in Advance Computing &amp;amp; Information Systems and an MSc in Space Applications &amp;amp; Technologies.
My technology interests apply to the following domains:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://tomchavakis.github.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tomchavakis.github.io/projects/</guid>
      <description>Go
geojson - Implementation of the GeoJSON protocol in GoLang (RFC 7946)
turf-go - A Go language port of Turf.js
geo-api- An API written in GO that covers basic GIS Functionality.
C#
nuget-license - .NET Core tool to print or save all the licenses of a project
encrypto -.NET Core Tool to encrypt/decrypt folders or files in a directory and text
Python
grib-downloader - Download Weather GRIB Files from NOMADS - NOAA </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading - Podcasts</title>
      <link>https://tomchavakis.github.io/other/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tomchavakis.github.io/other/</guid>
      <description>In the past, I read mainly technical books and scientific articles. During the unprecedented times of the pandemic, I started reading books and listening to podcasts and this is a list of what I have found interesting and I would like to share with you.
Books Tech The Go Programming Language by Alan A.A. Donovan, Brian W. Kernighan
Designing Data-Intensive Applications, by Martin Kleppmann
Software Engineering at Google, by Titus Winters, Tom Manshreck, Hyrum Wright</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
