<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Thomas Chavakis</title>
    <link>https://tomchavakis.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Thomas Chavakis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 23:37:43 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tomchavakis.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Go - Generics</title>
      <link>https://tomchavakis.github.io/posts/go-generics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 23:37:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tomchavakis.github.io/posts/go-generics/</guid>
      <description>Abstract In Go 1.18 which released on the 15th of March 2022 [5] added generics to the language, a long awaited feature in the Go Community.
The following proposal by Ian Lance Taylor is the design for adding generic programming using type parameters to the Go language.
This design has been proposed and accepted. This article presents basic functionality and examples of the Generics.
Type parameters With generics, you can declare and use functions or types that are written to work with any of a set of types provided by calling code[1].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual studio code extensions for teams</title>
      <link>https://tomchavakis.github.io/posts/visual-studio-code-for-coding-teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 11:40:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tomchavakis.github.io/posts/visual-studio-code-for-coding-teams/</guid>
      <description>What ? Visual Studio Code is a cross-platform code editor made by Microsoft. There are more than 30.000 Extensions available to the marketplace of the visual studio code which turns the tool into a powerful, multi-language and multipurpose IDE.
The teams need to have common tools for the day to day work. When you change programs it&amp;rsquo;s easy to get distracted, lose your focus and your purpose. With the following extensions, you can do the biggest part of your work within the visual studio code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Documentation Before Development</title>
      <link>https://tomchavakis.github.io/posts/documentation-before-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 12:18:30 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tomchavakis.github.io/posts/documentation-before-development/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Documentation Before Development (DBD), is an agile way of working within a software development team.
Every agile team in the software industry has to release products quickly and frequently, and usually documents the processes followed at the very end of the project.
The DBD process was created to address the problems arising when software teams start the delopment phase without analyzing in depth what is going to be delivered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to optimally alter mysql tables using percona-tools</title>
      <link>https://tomchavakis.github.io/posts/how-to-optimally-alter-mysql-tables-using-percona-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 12:13:30 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tomchavakis.github.io/posts/how-to-optimally-alter-mysql-tables-using-percona-tools/</guid>
      <description>Introduction You have to be very carefull when you are going to run an ALTER Table in the production Database. MySQL&amp;rsquo;s ALTER TABLE can become a serious problem especially with very large tables. Many people have experience with ALTER TABLE operations that have taken hours or days to complete.
From the MySQL documentation for ALTER TABLE:
ALTER TABLE changes the structure of a table. The operations are processed using one of the following algorithms:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
